PSA to all my performance coaches out there.
Your programming is not your issue.
What happens is you are not giving your athletes an amazing experience when they come to their
training session.
So let me put it like this.
Mostly you get so caught up in the reps, sets, exercise selection, and you have the personality
of a cardboard box.
Your athletes aren't confident, they're unsure of what they're doing, you're trying to get
so technical with them that you're missing the mark.
Instead, if you focus on building that athlete's confidence, you focus on building rapport
with them, make them have fun, stay engaged, that is the first step.
Next is your programming step.
So if you build that athlete's confidence, make sure that they have an amazing experience,
want to continue to come back, not only will it increase consistency, but also beyond that,
you build their confidence and you increase their buy-in, buy-in is going to then result
in more effort into your program.
With more effort, obviously you're going to have more intentful sessions.
So make sure that they're having an amazing experience every single time.
The other thing that I'll mention to you is the saying that I always say that I got from
my former mentor.
You can take the best program in the world and follow it with half-ass and you're going
to get half-ass results, or you can follow the most basic program in the world, follow
it with maximum intent, 100% focus, all-out effort, and that athlete's going to get better
results.
PSA to all my performance coaches out there, your programming is not your issue.